Inventory of the Diana Mitchell Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Academic materials and writings, 1966-2000 (Box 30-38: 15)
  - Writings, 1961-2000 (Folder 35-38:)
    - Who's Who: African Nationalist Leaders in (Rhodesia) Zimbabwe, various editions, 1974-1983 (Folder 36-38:)
      - Questionnaires, undated (Folder 37: 11)
      - Research, 1974-1977 (Folder 37: 12)
      - Research, 1968-1983 (Folder 38: 1-2)
    - Unpublished notebooks, written by viewing and analyzing Zimbabwean news broadcasts, 1999-2000 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969-2000 (Folder 38:)
    - 1969-1979 (Folder 38: 4)
    - 1993-2000 (Folder 38: 5)
- Subject file, 1953-2005 (Box 39-71: 4)
  Contains biographical data, news clippings, government documents, pamphlets, reports, magazines, press releases, and correspondence
  Arranged in two groups, Biographical files on African nationalist leaders and parties and General topics, then alphabetically by subject
  - Biographical files on African nationalist leaders and parties, 1962-2001 (Folder 39-48:)
    The labels "Box A," "Box B," etc. correspond to inventories of select documents, provided in Boxes 39-41, maintained in original order
    - "Box A" (Folder 39:)
      - Inventory (Folder 39: 1)
      - African National Council (ANC)-United African National Council (UANC), 1975-1979 (Folder 39: 2-5)
    - "Box B" (Folder 39:)
      - Inventory (Folder 39: 6)
      - Zimbabwe African National Union (ZANU)-Zimbabwe African People's Union (ZAPU), 1975-1994 (Folder 39: 7-10)
    - "Box C" (Folder 40:)
      - Inventory (Folder 40: 1)
      - General, 1975-1980 (Folder 40: 2-6)
    - "Box D": Mugabe, Robert, 1980-1995 (Folder 40: 7)
      Includes inventory
    - "Box E" (Folder 41:)
      - Inventory (Folder 41: 1)
      - General, 1974-1985 (Folder 41: 2-3)
    - "Box H" (Folder 41:)
      - Inventory (Folder 41: 4)
      - General, 1977-1997 (Folder 41: 5-8)
    - ANC (Folder 42:)
      - General, 1962-1978 (Folder 42: 1-2)
      - Pre-independence, Nationalist leaders M-N, 1963-2003 (Folder 42: 3-4)
      - Occasional paper, no. 2, circa 1975 (Folder 42: 5)
    - ANC/ZANU/ZAPU, 1975-1978 (Folder 43: 1-2)
    - ZANU-PF (Folder 43:)
      - General, clippings, 1984-2001 (Folder 43: 3)
      - Publications, 1977-1985 (Folder 43: 4)
      - Publications, 1975-1978 (Folder 44: 1)
    - Who's Who files (Folder 44-45:)
      - General--Political, 1983-2001 (Folder 44: 2-6)
      - Non-political office persons, 1978-1995 (Folder 45: 1-2)
      - Nationalists vignettes, 1990-2001 (Folder 45: 3-4)
    - Banana, Canaan, 1977-1997 (Folder 45: 5)
    - Boka, Roger, 1998 (Folder 45: 6)
    - Chinamano, Josiah and Ruth, 1959-2001 (Folder 46: 1)
    - Chitepo, Herbert, 1985-1997 (Folder 46: 2)
    - Clutton-Brock, Guy, 1977-1978 (Folder 46: 3)
      Includes photograph
    - Dakamela, Myinga, 1975 (Folder 46: 4)
    - Dongo, Margaret, 1994-1999 (Folder 46: 5)
    - Dumbutshena, Enoch, 1990-1999 (Folder 46: 6-8)
    - Dumbutshena, Enoch: Manuscript fragments of The Mad Guerrilla, 1990 (Folder 46: 9)
    - National heroes, 1989-1996 (Folder 46: 10)
    - Moyo, Jonathan, 1978-2002 (Folder 47: 1)
    - Mugabe, Robert, 1970-1990 (Folder 47: 2-5)
    - Musarawa, Willie, 1976-1989 (Folder 48: 1)
    - Nkomo, Joshua, 1976-1996 (Folder 48: 2)
    - Sithole, Ndabaningi, 1975-2001 (Folder 48: 3)
    - Sithole, Ndabaningi: ANC minutes of settlement talks, 1977-1978, collected and distributed by N. Sithole (Folder 48: 4-7)
  - General topics, 1953-2005 (Folder 49-71:)
    - African National Council, 1977-2001 (Folder 49: 1)
    - Arts, 1988-2001 (Folder 49: 2)
    - Australian High Commission, Harare, 1989-1990 (Folder 49: 3-7)
    - Australian High Commission, Harare, 1990-1991 (Folder 50: 1-2)
    - Banking, 1981-2002 (Folder 50: 3)
    - Biographical data, various, 1990 (Folder 50: 4)
    - Capricorn Africa Society, 1955; undated (Folder 50: 5)
    - Catholic Commission for Justice and Peace, 1979-1994 (Folder 50: 6)
    - Church, 1970 (Folder 50: 7)
    - Civil disorder, 1997-1998 (Folder 50: 8)
    - Civil service, 1996 (Folder 50: 9)
    - Constitution and National Constitutional Assembly, 1967-2001 (Folder 50: 10)
    - Constitution and National Constitutional Assembly, 1967-2001 (Contd.) (Folder 51: 1-5)
    - Constitution and National Constitutional Assembly, 1967-2001 (Contd.) (Folder 52: 1-6)
    - Constitution and National Constitutional Assembly, 2002 (Folder 53: 1)
    - Constitution--Rhodesia, 1959-1979 (Folder 53: 2-6)
    - Courtesy Drive, 1975 (Folder 53: 7)
    - Culture, 1988-2002 (Folder 53: 8)
    - Economy (Folder 54:)
      - General, 1980-1995 (Folder 54: 1)
      - Mark Rove reports, 1998-2002 (Folder 54: 2-7)
    - Education, 1965-1995 (Folder 54: 8)
    - Education, 1966-1975 (Folder 55: 1)
    - Epworth Mission, 1971 (Folder 55: 2)
    - Environment, 1990-1994 (Folder 55: 3)
    - Elections--General, 1979-2001 (Folder 55: 4)
    - Elections--general, 1979-2001 (Folder 55: 5)
    - Flag, 1968-1983 (Folder 55: 6)
    - Goodwin, Peter, 1996 (Folder 55: 7)
    - Handicrafts, 1969-1970 (Folder 55: 8)
    - Health (Folder 55:)
      - General, 1994-1995 (Folder 55: 9)
      - Abortion, 1994 (Folder 55: 10)
      - AIDS, 1994 (Folder 55: 11)
    - Human rights, 1988-2005 (Folder 55: 12-14)
    - Human rights, 1993-2001 (Folder 56: 1-3)
    - Indigenous Business Development Centre (IBDC), 1994-1995 (Folder 56: 4-5)
    - Katz, Alexander, 1998-2000 (Folder 56: 6)
    - Kabor, 1994 (Folder 57: 1)
    - Lancaster House, Constitutional Conference, 1979 (Folder 57: 2)
    - Land (Folder 57-58:)
      - General clippings, 1992-2001 (Folder 57: 3-5)
      - General clippings, 2001-2002 (Folder 58: 1-2)
      - Conference at University of London, 1998 (Folder 58: 3)
      - Resettlement, 1992-1994 (Folder 58: 4)
    - Law, 1990-2001 (Folder 58: 5-6)
    - Legislation--Rhodesia, 1961-1977 (Folder 59: 1-3)
    - Liberation War, 1973-1978 (Folder 59: 4)
    - Lutheran World Federation: Agriculture Co-Op Survey Project, 1983 (Folder 59: 5-6)
    - Media, 1995 (Folder 59: 7)
    - Media, 1977-2002 (Folder 60: 1-6)
    - Media, 1993-1999 (Folder 61: 1-2)
    - Muzorewa, Abel, 1976-1995 (Folder 61: 3)
    - Nationalism, 1969-1980 (Folder 61: 4-5)
    - Non-governmental organizations, 1990-2001 (Folder 61: 6-7)
    - Opposition parties, 1994-1995 (Folder 62: 1)
    - Parliament, Rhodesia and Zimbabwe, 1969-1998 (Folder 62: 2-6)
    - Phimster, Ian, 1980-1994 (Folder 62: 7)
    - Pre-independence, 1978-1980 (Folder 62: 8)
    - Propaganda, 1987-2002 (Folder 62: 9)
    - Race and racism, 1953-2002 (Folder 62: 10-12)
    - Race and racism, 1970-2002 (Folder 63: 1-4)
    - Rhodesia (Folder 63:)
      - General, 1957-1979 (Folder 63: 5)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs fact papers, 1977-1979 (Folder 63: 6)
      - Politics, miscellaneous, 1978-1979 (Folder 63: 7)
      - Prosecution of R. G. S. Simmonds, 1968-1974 (Folder 63: 8)
      - Religious groups, 1969-1976 (Folder 63: 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-2001 (Folder 63: 9)
    - Settlement (Folder 64:)
      - General, 1977-1979 (Folder 64: 1-2)
      - Council, 1972 (Folder 64: 3)
      - Proposals, 1966-1971 (Folder 64: 4)
      - Talks, 1977-1979 (Folder 64: 5-6)
    - Social welfare, 1995 (Folder 64: 7)
    - Speeches, 1957-1973 (Folder 64: 8)
    - South Africa, 1975-1990 (Folder 64: 9)
    - Stephenson, Francis, 1965-1980 (Folder 64: 10-11)
      Includes official documents relating to Ian Smith
    - Tourism, 1987-1989; undated (Folder 65: 1)
    - Trade unions, 1981-1998 (Folder 65: 2)
    - Tribal trust lands, 1970-1974 (Folder 65: 3)
    - Tribalism, 1994 (Folder 65: 4)
    - University of Zimbabwe, 1982-1995 (Folder 65: 5-6)
    - War veterans, 1990-2001 (Folder 65: 7-8)
    - Who's Who materials, 1986-2002 (Folder 65: 9)
    - Who's Who materials, 1992-2000 (Folder 66: 1-3)
    - Women, 1972-2001 (Folder 66: 4-9)
    - Writers, 1986-1994 (Folder 66: 10)
    - Zimbabwe (Folder 67-71:)
      - General, 1985-2001 (Folder 67: 1)
      - Department of Information, Press Statements, 1985-1986 (Folder 67: 2-5)
      - Department of Information, Press Statements, 1986-1988 (Folder 68: 1-6)
      - Department of Information, Press Statements, 1988-1990 (Folder 69: 1-8)
      - Department of Information, Press Statements, 1990-1993 (Folder 70: 1-8)
      - Reports, 2000 (Folder 71: 1)
    - Zimbabwe Africa National Union-Patriotic Front (ZANU-PF), 1995 (Folder 71: 2)
    - Zimbabwe Information Group printed matter, 1977-1980 (Folder 71: 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1981 (Folder 71: 4)
      Includes fragments of writings, script of unidentified play, and other research materials
- Personal file, 1982-1997 (Box 71:)
  Contains diary entries, correspondence, and invitations
  - Diary entries, 1992-1994 (Folder 71: 5)
  - Greeting cards and invitations, 1982-1991; undated (Folder 71: 6-7)
  - Personal correspondence, 1985-1997 (Folder 71: 8)
- Card file, 1956-1994 (Box 72-74:)
  Contains index cards with notes, biographical data, and reference materials, maintained in original order
  - Notes, citations, and related materials on African history, race relations, and research for Who's Who of African Nationalists, 1969-1994 (Folder 72-73:)
  - Alphabetical name file and biographical data on African leaders and political parties, 1956-1990 (Folder 74:)